<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/helen/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/helen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do We Get More Women on Company Boards?</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2021-08-how-do-we-get-more-women-on-company-boards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2021-08-how-do-we-get-more-women-on-company-boards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Women on Board? Family Policies, Quotas and Gender Diversity in Top Jobs.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2020-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-quotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2020-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-quotas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Policies, Quotas, and Gender Diversity with Dr Helen Kowalewska</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2021-05-family-policies-quotas-and-gender-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2021-05-family-policies-quotas-and-gender-diversity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breadwinning or on the Breadline? Female Breadwinners’ Economic Characteristics across 20 Welfare States</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2020-breadwinning-or-on-the-breadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2020-breadwinning-or-on-the-breadline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configurations of Gender Inequality and Segregation in Employment Across Welfare Regimes</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2021-configurations-of-gender-inequality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2021-configurations-of-gender-inequality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female-Breadwinner Families on the Breadline.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-female-breadwinners-on-the-breadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-female-breadwinners-on-the-breadline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing women on board: How government policies can improve gender diversity in top jobs</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-11-inet-equal-pay-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-11-inet-equal-pay-day/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female-Breadwinner Families on the Breadline</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-09-female-breadwinner-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-09-female-breadwinner-families/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20th November is Equal Pay Day</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-10-inet-bringing-women-on-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2020-12-10-inet-bringing-women-on-board/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Women on Board: The Social Policy Implications of Gender Diversity in Top Jobs.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-bringing-women-on-board-social-policy-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-bringing-women-on-board-social-policy-implications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update September 2020</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2020-09-update-september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2020-09-update-september-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month I returned to work following the birth of my first child six months ago. It is an exciting but busy time trying to balance my career and childcare (and everything else amid a pandemic). I feel the experience will only make me a better researcher given my areas of interest and how productive I am forced to be when I do get the chance to carry out some research and write.
During my maternity leave, I had a paper, co-authored with Agnese Vitali, accepted for publication in the Journal of European Social Policy. Through descriptive and regression analyses of Luxembourg Income Study microdata covering 20 industrialised countries, we find that female-breadwinner couples are economically disadvantaged compared with all other couple-types - including their male-breadwinner counterparts - across all welfare regimes. The paper will be available online soon. In the meantime, you can check out our working paper version: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lisdatacenter.org/wps/liswps/769.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www.lisdatacenter.org/wps/liswps/769.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I have just resubmitted a paper to another journal following minor revisions. The paper is part of my ESRC New Investigator Grant on the ‘welfare-state paradox’: work-family policies that bring women into the workforce also undermine women’s access to top-level positions. The article is a fuzzy-set Qualitative Comparative Analysis of the associations between ‘women-friendly’ state interventions and women’s share of board and executive positions across 22 industrialised countries. Overall, the analysis finds limited evidence in support of a welfare-state paradox. Moreover, widespread childcare services are associated with gender-diverse boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am continuing to work on my ESRC New Investigator Grant, looking at patterns of gender segregation in employment across different countries. I am also developing additional papers with colleagues on female breadwinners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Women on Board(s) to Create ‘Women-Friendly’ Workplaces</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-12-create-woman-friendly-workplaces-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-12-create-woman-friendly-workplaces-blog-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Southampton Research Journey: From Undergrad to Postdoc</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-09-southampton-research-journey-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-09-southampton-research-journey-blog-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Women on Board? Family Policies, Quotas, and Gender Diversity in Top Jobs</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-and-quotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-and-quotas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Women-Friendly&#39; State Interventions and Occupational Gender Segregation: Paradise or Paradox?</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/esrc-new-investigators-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/esrc-new-investigators-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Comparative social-science researchers, the press, and politicians often hail Scandinavian societies as a gender equality ‘paradise’ and a role model for the UK because of their generous public sectors. Yet, an influential body of research has proposed a welfare state ‘paradox’ or gendered ‘trade-offs’. The argument goes that while ‘women-friendly’ welfare states achieve high female employment rates, they also make it harder for women to break into (better) male-dominated jobs by increasing discrimination against women and funnelling women into female-typed public-sector positions (e.g., Mandel and Semyonov, 2006; Pettit and Hook, 2005). However, there is a far from a consensus on this issue, with studies based on more recent data finding no empirical evidence in support of gendered trade-offs or paradoxes (e.g., Brady et al., 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ESRC-funded project contributes to this debate in three main ways. First, it makes use of up-to-date data to better understand the contingent relationships and potential tensions between different dimensions of gender inequality and segregation in employment through a cluster analysis of multiple outcomes for women’s employment across 24 advanced economies. Second, the project moves beyond the methodological nationalism of current research to consider how national-level policies, in interaction with regional-level conditions, shape women’s employment outcomes through a multilevel regression analysis of European Social Survey data. Third, the project investigates some of the underlying mechanisms through which women’s careers are potentially adversely affected by work-family policies via a secondary analysis of qualitative data in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit: Caroline Lucas criticised over all-female cabinet plan</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-08-bbc-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-08-bbc-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Oxford/ESRC grant</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to announce that later this month I’ll be moving to the Institute for New Economic thinking at the University of Oxford. I’ll be a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working on the Oxford Martin Programme on Inequality and Prosperity, looking at inclusive growth. You can find more information about the research programme &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oxfordmartin.ox.ac.uk/research/programmes/inequality-prosperity&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I have been awarded a New Investigator Grant from the Economic and Social Research Council. The grant is titled ”Women-Friendly’ State Interventions and Occupational Gender Segregation: Paradise or Paradox?’ (no. ES/S016058/1). I’ll be re-examining the welfare state ‘paradox’ – the idea that more ‘women-friendly’ welfare policies make it harder for women to reach the best jobs – using up-to-date data and novel methods and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2019 - Paper on how smashing the glass ceiling benefits all women</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to announce that the third paper from my PhD has been accepted for publication in Journal of Social Policy. The paper argues that analyses of gender and welfare states should be broadened to include women’s share of corporate board and executive positions and the policies that help to address the lack of gender diversity in such positions. Bringing more women into the most powerful jobs can lead to more ‘female-friendly’ workplace policies, practices, and cultures (e.g. workplace childcare facilities, sexual-harassment training), which can contribute to addressing some of the gendered ‘social risks’ (e.g. work/family conflicts, violations of body rights) faced by women further down the labour market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Martin Programme on Inequality and Prosperity.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/oxford-martin-inequality-and-prosperity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/oxford-martin-inequality-and-prosperity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female Breadwinner Families in Europe</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/female-breadwinner-families-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/female-breadwinner-families-in-europe/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Policies to Support Women’s Employment and Achieve Gender-Friendly Workplaces</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/social-policies-to-support-womens-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/social-policies-to-support-womens-employment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project: (1) presented a social rationale for gender diversity in the boardroom,
which posits that putting more women on boards can help to combat the sexual
subordination of women in the workplace and reduce the incidence of social risk for
women at lower levels of the labour market; (2) analysed the policy factors that help
us to understand why some advanced economies have been more successful than
others in addressing women’s underrepresentation on corporate boards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the project was conceptual and went beyond the business case and
justice or ‘fairness’ arguments for gender-diverse boards by proposing a social
rationale. This involved synthesising evidence from across multiple disciplines to
show the relevance of women’s board membership - and the policies designed to
increase it - for scholars and policymakers interested in women’s ‘social risks’,
including employment/care conflicts, economic dependence on a partner, inadequate
social security coverage, and low wages. Women in board and executive roles signal
that the organisation values women and are often ‘agents of change’ in pushing for
organisational policies, practices, and cultures that improve the ‘women-friendliness’
of workplaces. These include measures to combat sexual harassment, action to
reduce gender wage disparities in the firm and flexible working arrangements, which
can benefit all women in the company, including the lowest earners. This argument
strengthens the case for greater government action in its role as regulator of market
actors’ behaviours through legislation designed to break the ‘glass ceiling’ at the top
of companies. You can read the peer-reviewed paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-social-policy/article/abs/bringing-women-on-board-the-social-policy-implications-of-gender-diversity-in-top-jobs/59FE25C7DD363901F07AE089B79BFA2D&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the project was an empirical analysis of the policies associated
with a ‘critical mass’ of women on boards. An influential body of work has identified a
‘welfare-state paradox’: work–family policies that bring women into the workforce
also undermine women’s access to top jobs. Missing from this literature is a
consideration of how welfare-state interventions impact on women’s representation
at the board-level specifically, rather than managerial and lucrative positions more
generally. This research contributed to addressing this ‘gap’ by examining how
welfare-state interventions combine with gender boardroom quotas and regulations
in (not) bringing a critical mass of women onto boards. It did this through a fuzzy-set
Qualitative Comparative Analysis of 22 advanced economies, which involved
analysing countries as ‘packages’ of policies and looking at the shares of women on
boards that are associated with each package. Macro-level data were collated
mainly from various Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development
databases. Overall, the analysis found limited evidence in support of a welfare-state
paradox. Rather, countries are unlikely to achieve a critical mass of women on
boards in the absence of adequate childcare services. Furthermore, ‘hard’,
mandatory gender boardroom quotas are not necessary for achieving more women
on boards; ‘soft’, voluntary recommendations can also work under certain family
policy constellations. You can read the peer-reviewed paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0950017020971221&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding: The &lt;a href=&#34;https://esrc.ukri.org&#34;&gt;Economic and Social Research Council&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.southcoastdtp.ac.uk&#34;&gt;South Coast Doctoral
Training Partnership&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coverage in The Independent</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-05-independent-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 22:55:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-05-independent-coverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our findings shed doubt on popular depictions of female breadwinners as high-earning, empowered women – instead they are often lower-educated,” Dr Kowalewska told the British Sociological Association’s annual conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to say that my research on female breadwinners, co-authored with Dr Agnese Vitali, was featured in The Independent on 1 May! Here is a link to the full article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/household-earnings-sole-women-men-gender-us-west-europe-salary-a8894426.html&#34;&gt;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/household-earnings-sole-women-men-gender-us-west-europe-salary-a8894426.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about this research here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://helenkowalewska.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/BSA-Presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;https://helenkowalewska.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/BSA-Presentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan on submitting the paper for journal publication in the next month or two, so watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK households where women are sole earner significantly poorer than in US and western Europe, research finds.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-06-independent-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-06-independent-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breadwinning or On the Breadline? Female Breadwinners’ Economic Characteristics across 20 Welfare States</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-breadwinning-or-on-the-breadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-breadwinning-or-on-the-breadline/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female breadwinner households ‘significantly poorer’</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-workingmums-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-workingmums-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Households where the woman is the sole earner are significantly poorer, says research.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-phys.org-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-phys.org-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 – BSA conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 25 April I presented a paper that I co-authored with Dr Agnese Vitali (University of Trento) at the annual British Sociological Conference at Glasgow Caledonian University. The paper is titled Breadwinning or on the Breadline? Female Breadwinners’ Economic Characteristics across 20 Welfare States. We critique existing research on work/family arrangements and welfare states for overlooking an increasingly prevalent arrangement across couples, which is that of the female-breadwinner family model. We show that, contrary to popular depictions of female breadwinners as empowered, high-earning women, many are ‘on the breadline’, in that they are among the poorest of all households. What’s more, women who are breadwinners earn less as individuals, work fewer hours, and are more likely to work in lower-paying occupations and less likely to be managers/professionals than male breadwinners. See the press release from the BSA and my slides on the ‘Publications’ tab for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2019 – Nordic Welfare Research Conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 14-15 March I attended the Nordic Welfare Research Conference at the University of Helsinki and presented my latest research. The research examines how family and labour-market policies shape women’s access to corporate board and executive positions across 24 OECD countries via a fuzzy-set analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a strange experience presenting research on the lack of women in the most powerful positions while surrounded by paintings of white old men on the walls. Funny when you see comments like those claiming white men are becoming an ‘endangered species’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to continue developing the paper and will be presenting again at the 2019 European Sociological Conference in Manchester (20-23 August).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work/Family Arrangements across the OECD: Incorporating the Female-Breadwinner Model</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-work-arrangements-across-the-oecd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-work-arrangements-across-the-oecd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference on Female Breadwinning, London</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12-13 December 2018, I attended the Female-Breadwinner Families in Europe workshop organised by Dr Agnese Vitali. The day brought together researchers and policy influencers interested in the rise in female breadwinning. A key lesson from the presentations is that we need to distinguish between ‘pure’ female breadwinner families, in which the woman is the only earner while the man is unemployed, and women-as-main-earner families, in which the woman out-earns the man, but both are employed. These two family-types typically differ in terms of education, income, and wellbeing – while the former is associated with male unemployment and higher poverty risks, the latter is associated with choice and higher earnings. Click here
to find out more about the paper on female breadwinning that I’m co-authoring with Dr Vitali, which I’ll also be presenting at the 2019 British Sociological Association Conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethnicity and Social Housing Allocation in England: An Exploratory Analysis of CORE</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2018-ethnicity-and-social-housing-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2018-ethnicity-and-social-housing-report/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the ‘Train-First’/‘Work-First’ Dichotomy: How Welfare States Help or Hinder Maternal Employment.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-beyond-the-train-first-work-first-dichotomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-beyond-the-train-first-work-first-dichotomy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Active Welfare State: Towards a Gender-Friendly Approach.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-phd-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-phd-thesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What women don’t want: how many countries still ‘mummy track’ women</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2016-11-esrc-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2016-11-esrc-blog-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diminishing Returns: Lone Mothers’ Work Incentives and Incomes under the Coalition.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2015-diminishing-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2015-diminishing-returns/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
