<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 23:57:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare State Interventions and Occupational Gender Segregation: Paradise or Paradox?</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/esrc-new-investigators-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/esrc-new-investigators-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welfare states enable women&amp;rsquo;s employment through the family policies they provide and the jobs they create. Hence, comparative social-science researchers, the press, and politicians hail Scandinavian societies as a gender equality &amp;lsquo;paradise&amp;rsquo; and a role model for the UK because of their generous public sectors (e.g. Esping-Andersen, 2016). Yet, prior research has suggested a welfare state &amp;lsquo;paradox&amp;rsquo;: while &amp;lsquo;women-friendly&amp;rsquo; welfare states achieve high female employment rates, they also frustrate women&amp;rsquo;s access to male-dominated jobs by increasing discrimination against women and funnelling women into female-typed public-sector positions (Mandel and Semyonov, 2006).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, most studies on the welfare state paradox use data from 2000 or earlier. But a lot has changed since then. Nordic labour markets are no longer the most gender-segregated and, on some measures of segregation, outperform less women-friendly countries, including the UK. Thus, the relationship between women-friendly measures and gender employment segregation appears more complex than paradox theory predicts. The purpose of this project is to shed light on such complexity through the following objectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To situate the relationship between ‘women-friendly’ social policies and gender employment segregation within the broader macro-level context. Do generous family policies always lead to segregation? Or can certain conditions (e.g. gender boardroom quotas) help to &amp;lsquo;cancel out&amp;rsquo; the negative impact of family policies on women&amp;rsquo;s careers? Up-to-date data will be analysed using methods that have not been used to explore the welfare state paradox before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To go beyond the country and clarify how the impacts of welfare states on women&amp;rsquo;s careers vary within countries according to a region&amp;rsquo;s specific economic and social context using multilevel regression models. Research has shown that occupational sex segregation is contingent on the structure of local labour markets, their sociodemographic composition and the dominant gender-role ideology (Perales and Vidal, 2015). By examining the applicability of paradox theory to NUTS regions across 20 countries, the research can provide an evidence base for locally tailored policy solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To carry out an intersectional analysis of women-friendly policies and gender employment segregation. Intersectionality posits that women are not a homogeneous group, as gender interacts with other dimensions of &amp;lsquo;difference&amp;rsquo; (e.g. class) in shaping people&amp;rsquo;s experiences (Crenshaw, 1991). Prior studies have examined the outcomes of gender/class intersections (e.g. Korpi et al., 2013). The project will build on these studies by interrogating the underlying mechanisms that determine these outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brexit: Caroline Lucas criticised over all-female cabinet plan</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-08-bbc-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-08-bbc-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Oxford/ESRC grant</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to announce that later this month I’ll be moving to the Institute for New Economic thinking at the University of Oxford. I’ll be a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working on the Oxford Martin Programme on Inequality and Prosperity, looking at inclusive growth. You can find more information about the research programme &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oxfordmartin.ox.ac.uk/research/programmes/inequality-prosperity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I have been awarded a New Investigator Grant from the Economic and Social Research Council. The grant is titled ”Women-Friendly’ State Interventions and Occupational Gender Segregation: Paradise or Paradox?’ (no. ES/S016058/1). I’ll be re-examining the welfare state ‘paradox’ – the idea that more ‘women-friendly’ welfare policies make it harder for women to reach the best jobs – using up-to-date data and novel methods and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2019 - Paper on how smashing the glass ceiling benefits all women</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to announce that the third paper from my PhD has been accepted for publication in Journal of Social Policy. The paper argues that analyses of gender and welfare states should be broadened to include women’s share of corporate board and executive positions and the policies that help to address the lack of gender diversity in such positions. Bringing more women into the most powerful jobs can lead to more ‘female-friendly’ workplace policies, practices, and cultures (e.g. workplace childcare facilities, sexual-harassment training), which can contribute to addressing some of the gendered ‘social risks’ (e.g. work/family conflicts, violations of body rights) faced by women further down the labour market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford Martin Programme on Inequality and Prosperity.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/oxford-martin-inequality-and-prosperity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/oxford-martin-inequality-and-prosperity/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Bringing Women on Board: The Social Policy Implications of Gender Diversity in Top Jobs.’</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-bringing-women-on-board-trickle-down-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2019-bringing-women-on-board-trickle-down-benefits/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female Breadwinner Families in Europe</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/female-breadwinner-families-in-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/female-breadwinner-families-in-europe/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Policies to Support Women’s Employment and Achieve Gender-Friendly Workplaces</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/social-policies-to-support-womens-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/project/social-policies-to-support-womens-employment/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coverage in The Independent</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-05-independent-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 22:55:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-05-independent-coverage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our findings shed doubt on popular depictions of female breadwinners as high-earning, empowered women – instead they are often lower-educated,” Dr Kowalewska told the British Sociological Association’s annual conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to say that my research on female breadwinners, co-authored with Dr Agnese Vitali, was featured in The Independent on 1 May! Here is a link to the full article: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/household-earnings-sole-women-men-gender-us-west-europe-salary-a8894426.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/household-earnings-sole-women-men-gender-us-west-europe-salary-a8894426.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about this research here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://helenkowalewska.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/BSA-Presentation.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://helenkowalewska.uk/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/BSA-Presentation.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan on submitting the paper for journal publication in the next month or two, so watch this space…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK households where women are sole earner significantly poorer than in US and western Europe, research finds.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-06-independent-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-06-independent-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female breadwinner households ‘significantly poorer’</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-workingmums-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-workingmums-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Households where the woman is the sole earner are significantly poorer, says research.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-phys.org-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2019-04-phys.org-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 – BSA conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 25 April I presented a paper that I co-authored with Dr Agnese Vitali (University of Trento) at the annual British Sociological Conference at Glasgow Caledonian University. The paper is titled Breadwinning or on the Breadline? Female Breadwinners’ Economic Characteristics across 20 Welfare States. We critique existing research on work/family arrangements and welfare states for overlooking an increasingly prevalent arrangement across couples, which is that of the female-breadwinner family model. We show that, contrary to popular depictions of female breadwinners as empowered, high-earning women, many are ‘on the breadline’, in that they are among the poorest of all households. What’s more, women who are breadwinners earn less as individuals, work fewer hours, and are more likely to work in lower-paying occupations and less likely to be managers/professionals than male breadwinners. See the press release from the BSA and my slides on the ‘Publications’ tab for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2019 – Nordic Welfare Research Conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 14-15 March I attended the Nordic Welfare Research Conference at the University of Helsinki and presented my latest research. The research examines how family and labour-market policies shape women’s access to corporate board and executive positions across 24 OECD countries via a fuzzy-set analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a strange experience presenting research on the lack of women in the most powerful positions while surrounded by paintings of white old men on the walls. Funny when you see comments like those claiming white men are becoming an ‘endangered species’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to continue developing the paper and will be presenting again at the 2019 European Sociological Conference in Manchester (20-23 August).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference on Female Breadwinning, London</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12-13 December 2018, I attended the Female-Breadwinner Families in Europe workshop organised by Dr Agnese Vitali. The day brought together researchers and policy influencers interested in the rise in female breadwinning. A key lesson from the presentations is that we need to distinguish between ‘pure’ female breadwinner families, in which the woman is the only earner while the man is unemployed, and women-as-main-earner families, in which the woman out-earns the man, but both are employed. These two family-types typically differ in terms of education, income, and wellbeing – while the former is associated with male unemployment and higher poverty risks, the latter is associated with choice and higher earnings. Click here
to find out more about the paper on female breadwinning that I’m co-authoring with Dr Vitali, which I’ll also be presenting at the 2019 British Sociological Association Conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the ‘Train-First’/‘Work-First’ Dichotomy: How Welfare States Help or Hinder Maternal Employment.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-beyond-the-train-first-work-first-dichotomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-beyond-the-train-first-work-first-dichotomy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Active Welfare State: Towards a Gender-Friendly Approach.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-phd-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2017-phd-thesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What women don’t want: how many countries still ‘mummy track’ women</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2016-11-esrc-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/media/2016-11-esrc-blog-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diminishing Returns: Lone Mothers’ Work Incentives and Incomes under the Coalition.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2015-diminishing-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/publication/2015-diminishing-returns/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Women on Board? Family Policies, Quotas, and Gender Diversity in Top Jobs.</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-and-quotas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/talk/2019-bringing-women-on-board-family-policies-and-quotas/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
