<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Conferences on Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/tags/conferences/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Conferences on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 – BSA conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-04-bsa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 25 April I presented a paper that I co-authored with Dr Agnese Vitali (University of Trento) at the annual British Sociological Conference at Glasgow Caledonian University. The paper is titled Breadwinning or on the Breadline? Female Breadwinners’ Economic Characteristics across 20 Welfare States. We critique existing research on work/family arrangements and welfare states for overlooking an increasingly prevalent arrangement across couples, which is that of the female-breadwinner family model. We show that, contrary to popular depictions of female breadwinners as empowered, high-earning women, many are ‘on the breadline’, in that they are among the poorest of all households. What’s more, women who are breadwinners earn less as individuals, work fewer hours, and are more likely to work in lower-paying occupations and less likely to be managers/professionals than male breadwinners. See the press release from the BSA and my slides on the ‘Publications’ tab for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2019 – Nordic Welfare Research Conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 14-15 March I attended the Nordic Welfare Research Conference at the University of Helsinki and presented my latest research. The research examines how family and labour-market policies shape women’s access to corporate board and executive positions across 24 OECD countries via a fuzzy-set analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a strange experience presenting research on the lack of women in the most powerful positions while surrounded by paintings of white old men on the walls. Funny when you see comments like those claiming white men are becoming an ‘endangered species’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to continue developing the paper and will be presenting again at the 2019 European Sociological Conference in Manchester (20-23 August).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference on Female Breadwinning, London</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2018-12-conference-on-female-breadwinning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12-13 December 2018, I attended the Female-Breadwinner Families in Europe workshop organised by Dr Agnese Vitali. The day brought together researchers and policy influencers interested in the rise in female breadwinning. A key lesson from the presentations is that we need to distinguish between ‘pure’ female breadwinner families, in which the woman is the only earner while the man is unemployed, and women-as-main-earner families, in which the woman out-earns the man, but both are employed. These two family-types typically differ in terms of education, income, and wellbeing – while the former is associated with male unemployment and higher poverty risks, the latter is associated with choice and higher earnings. Click here
to find out more about the paper on female breadwinning that I’m co-authoring with Dr Vitali, which I’ll also be presenting at the 2019 British Sociological Association Conference in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
