<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gender and the Welfare State on Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/tags/gender-and-the-welfare-state/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gender and the Welfare State on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/tags/gender-and-the-welfare-state/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>University of Oxford/ESRC grant</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-university-of-oxford-esrc-grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to announce that later this month I’ll be moving to the Institute for New Economic thinking at the University of Oxford. I’ll be a Postdoctoral Research Fellow working on the Oxford Martin Programme on Inequality and Prosperity, looking at inclusive growth. You can find more information about the research programme &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oxfordmartin.ox.ac.uk/research/programmes/inequality-prosperity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I have been awarded a New Investigator Grant from the Economic and Social Research Council. The grant is titled ”Women-Friendly’ State Interventions and Occupational Gender Segregation: Paradise or Paradox?’ (no. ES/S016058/1). I’ll be re-examining the welfare state ‘paradox’ – the idea that more ‘women-friendly’ welfare policies make it harder for women to reach the best jobs – using up-to-date data and novel methods and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2019 - Paper on how smashing the glass ceiling benefits all women</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-08-smashing-the-glass-ceiling-benefits-all-women/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to announce that the third paper from my PhD has been accepted for publication in Journal of Social Policy. The paper argues that analyses of gender and welfare states should be broadened to include women’s share of corporate board and executive positions and the policies that help to address the lack of gender diversity in such positions. Bringing more women into the most powerful jobs can lead to more ‘female-friendly’ workplace policies, practices, and cultures (e.g. workplace childcare facilities, sexual-harassment training), which can contribute to addressing some of the gendered ‘social risks’ (e.g. work/family conflicts, violations of body rights) faced by women further down the labour market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2019 – Nordic Welfare Research Conference</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/post/2019-03-nordic-welfare-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 14-15 March I attended the Nordic Welfare Research Conference at the University of Helsinki and presented my latest research. The research examines how family and labour-market policies shape women’s access to corporate board and executive positions across 24 OECD countries via a fuzzy-set analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a strange experience presenting research on the lack of women in the most powerful positions while surrounded by paintings of white old men on the walls. Funny when you see comments like those claiming white men are becoming an ‘endangered species’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to continue developing the paper and will be presenting again at the 2019 European Sociological Conference in Manchester (20-23 August).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
