<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Take-Parts on Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/take-part/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Take-Parts on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:57:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/take-part/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Take part in research on job-seeking experiences for women over 50 
</title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/take-part/too-old-to-hire-too-young-to-retire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 23:57:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/take-part/too-old-to-hire-too-young-to-retire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We’re looking for interviewees to share their experiences for a study on
job-seeking among women aged 50+.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./image.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;woman shopping for food&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;study-information&#34;&gt;Study Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With your help, this study seeks to better understand how women aged 50+ in the
UK today are navigating the transition into paid work after unemployment or time
away from the labour market for other reasons, such as caregiving. We aim to
find out how these experiences are shaped by key life events in women’s pasts
and might vary by certain characteristics, like skill level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eligibility&#34;&gt;Eligibility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be eligible, you must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a woman aged 50+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be looking for paid work while &lt;strong&gt;not employed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are eligible to take part whether you’re still looking for work, have
recently found a job, or have stopped job-hunting for other reasons, such as
early retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not eligible to take part if you are/were employed during your job
search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-involved-in-the-study&#34;&gt;What’s involved in the study&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interview lasting around 1-2 hours at a date, time, and location of your
choice. The interview can be online or in person, it’s up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-youll-get-for-taking-part&#34;&gt;What you’ll get for taking part&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants will get £15 for their time and any expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll also be helping researchers to better understand the specific experiences
of women in moving back into paid work during their 50s and 60s. Most research
to date has focused on younger age groups or men over 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your participation can inform policies that better support the specific needs of
women experiencing unemployment and re-employment in their 50s and 60s. Your
participation can also increase awareness among employers about some of the
barriers women aged 50+ might face in finding work, so they can address these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might also help other women going through this transition to hear about your
experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;confidentiality&#34;&gt;Confidentiality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All information will be treated in the strictest confidence and stored in
accordance with current UK data protection legislation. As a participant, you’ll
have access to your data on request.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your name and any other identifying information will &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; be disclosed or
identifiable in any presentation or publication of the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-sign-up&#34;&gt;How to sign up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in taking part, please click the button below and fill in
the questionnaire to register your interest (approx. 10-15 minutes).
All the information received will be treated in the strictest confidence. We’ll
get back to you within two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;col-12 text-center&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://forms.gle/ANQhvasxM4bH1kpe9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; type=&#34;button&#34;
class=&#34;btn btn-primary p-3&#34;&gt;Register your interest&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this study, please contact the lead researcher,
Dr Helen Kowalewska, via email at &lt;a
href=&#34;mailto:hk775@bath.ac.uk&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hk775@bath.ac.uk&#34;&gt;hk775@bath.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1 This study has been reviewed and given a favourable opinion
by the University of Bath Social Science Research Ethics Committee [ref4885-7593].&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
