<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Helen Kowalewska</title>
    <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Helen Kowalewska</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Helen Kowalewska &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/helen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/helen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a Postdoctoral Fellow at the Department of Social Policy and Intervention and the Institute for New Economic Thinking at the University of Oxford. I’m also affiliated with Nuffield College. I recently returned from maternity leave following the birth of my first child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am working on a New Investigator Grant funded by the Economic and Social Research Council. The project looks at the relationship between labour market and family policies and women’s employment position across advanced economies using qualitative and quantitative methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also working on project on female breadwinners across advanced economies with my co-author Agnese Vitali (University of Trento). In our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lisdatacenter.org/wps/liswps/769.pdf&#34;&gt;latest paper&lt;/a&gt;, forthcoming in Journal of European Social Policy, we find that female-breadwinner couples – defined as those in which the woman is in paid work and the man is not – are economically disadvantaged compared with all other couple-types, including their male-breadwinner counterparts, across all welfare regimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to my current position, I held postdoc positions at the University of Southampton, where I also received my &lt;a href=&#34;https://eprints.soton.ac.uk/417383/1/Helen_Kowalewska_Minor_Corrections.pdf&#34;&gt;ESRC-funded PhD&lt;/a&gt;  in 2018. The thesis sought to bring a gendered perspective to debates on labour market ‘activation’. For this, I won the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.southampton.ac.uk/socsci/news/2016/10/social-science-researcher-wins-top-european-award.page&#34;&gt;Doctoral Researcher Prize&lt;/a&gt;, awarded by the Journal of European Social Policy and European Network for Social Policy Analysis for ‘exciting, innovative and scholarly’ work. Other papers from my PhD have been published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/social-policy-and-society/article/diminishing-returns-lone-mothers-financial-work-incentives-and-incomes-under-the-coalition/52B87AB5F1B0A9006AD78D1BE4E20D6E&#34;&gt;Social Policy and Society&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-social-policy/article/bringing-women-on-board-the-social-policy-implications-of-gender-diversity-in-top-jobs/59FE25C7DD363901F07AE089B79BFA2D&#34;&gt;Journal of Social Policy&lt;/a&gt;. I also hold an MSc in Social Policy (Distinction) and BSc in Politics (First), both from the University of Southampton.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/agnese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://helenkowalewska.uk/authors/agnese/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
